marketoracle.co.uk 2019-06-15

# The Market Oracle ::

## Introduction

The site editor takes your right to privacy seriously, and wants you to feel comfortable using this web site. This privacy policy deals with personally-identifiable information (referred to as "data" below) that may be collected by this site. This policy does not apply to other entities that are not owned or controlled by the site editor, nor does it apply to persons that are not employees or agents of the site editor, or that are not under the site editor's control. Please take time to read this site's [Terms of use](http://www.marketoracle.co.uk/module-Legal.html).

## 1\. Collection of data

Registration for an account on this site and for it's associated newsletter requires only a valid **e-mail address** and a user name that has not been chosen already. You are not required to provide any other information if you do not want to. Please be aware that the user name you choose, the e-mail address you provide and any other information you enter may render you personally identifiable, and may possibly be displayed on this web site intentionally (depending on choices you make during the registration process, or depending on the way in which the site is configured) or unintentionally (subsequent to a successful act of intrusion by a third party). As on many web sites, the site editor may also automatically receive general information that is contained in server log files, such as your IP address, and cookie information. Information about how advertising may be served on this site is set forth below.

## 2\. Use of data

Data may be used to customize and improve your user experience on this site. Efforts will be made to prevent your data being made available to third parties unless (i) provided for otherwise in this Privacy Policy; (ii) your consent is obtained, such as when you choose to opt-in or opt-out for the sharing of data; (iii) a service provided on our site requires interaction with a third party, or is provided by a third party, such as an application service provider; (iv) pursuant to legal action or law enforcement; (v) it is found that your use of this site violates the site editor's policy, terms of service, or other usage guidelines, or if it is deemed reasonably necessary by the site editor to protect the site editor's legal rights and/or property; or (vi) this site is purchased by a third party, in which case that third party will be able to use the data in the same manner as set forth in this policy. In the event you choose to use links displayed on this web site to visit other web sites, you are advised to read the privacy policies published on those sites. 

You are registered to our newsletter either via the Marketoracle.co.uk or Marketoracle.info, that the MarketOracle sends from time to time. You can un-register your email from our mailing list at any time by sending an email from the designated email address with the subject line UNSUBSCRIBE to newsletter@marketoracle.co.uk. We will on reciept remove your email from our list and no further emails will be sent. However, occastionally an UNSUBCRIBE email does not get through to us, so you may need to send it a second time if the first UNSUBSCRIBE message fails to be acted upon.

## 3\. Cookies

Like many web sites, this web site sets and uses cookies to enhance your user experience and as an essential part of this sites function. These cookies are annoymous and not used to identify users. Registered users have cookies stored only to enable log-ins for the posting of comments and for the function of any other service that may be provided to logged in users.

Advertisements may display on this web site and, if so, may set and access cookies on your computer; such cookies are subject to the privacy policy of the parties providing the advertisement. However, the parties providing the advertising do not have access to this site's cookies. We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and would like to know your options in relation to·not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.  

## 4\. Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

## 5\. Links to other websites

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

## 6\. Controlling your personal information

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting if you tell us that you wish this to happen.

You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. A small fee will be payable. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please write to [address].

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us as soon as possible at the above address. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.

## 7\. Minors

The site editor does not allow persons who are aged sixteen or younger to become members of this site. For more information, please contact [the site administrator](mailto:site_admin@marketoracle.co.uk).

## 8\. Editing or deleting your account information

You are provided with the ability to edit the information stored for your user account information during registration, by visiting [your user account control panel](http://www.marketoracle.co.uk/user.html). You can request that your user account be deleted; to do so, please contact [the site administrator](mailto:site_admin@marketoracle.co.uk). Content or other data that you may have provided, and that is not stored within your user account, such as comments and articles published, may continue to remain on the site at the site editor's discretion, even after your user account is deleted. Please see the site's [Terms of use](http://www.marketoracle.co.uk/module-Legal.html) for more information.

## 9\. Changes to this privacy policy

Changes may be made to this policy from time to time. You will be notified of substantial changes to this policy either by through the posting of a prominent announcement on the site, and/or by a mail message sent to the e-mail address you have provided, which is stored within your user settings.

## 10\. NO GUARANTEES

While this privacy policy states standards for maintenance of data, and while efforts will be made to meet the said standards, the site editor is not in a position to guarantee compliance with these standards. There may be factors beyond the site editor's control that may result in disclosure of data. Consquently, the site editor offers no warranties or representations as regards maintenance or non-disclosure of data.

## 11\. Contact information

If you have any questions about this policy or about this web site, please feel free to contact [the site administrator](mailto:site_admin@marketoracle.co.uk).
